<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://marsh.pw/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<title>
Michael Marsh
</title>
<link>
http://marsh.pw/
</link>
<description>
Professional Internet User
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Sun, 28 Jun 2015 15:43:38 -0400
</lastBuildDate>
<author>
Michael Marsh
</author>
<item>
<guid>
http://marsh.pw/posts/2015-06-28-a-day-in-a-modern-alienated-technological-life.html
</guid>
<link>
http://marsh.pw/posts/2015-06-28-a-day-in-a-modern-alienated-technological-life.html
</link>
<title>
A Day in a Modern, Alienated Technological Life
</title>
<description>
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;morning&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Morning&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I awaken in the morning,  sluggish from the poor quality of sleep I so unjustly got. Although I had every intention of getting some solid REM cycles, my laptop decided at the last minute that I was to watch a movie before I went to bed. It proceeded to hold me on my couch against my will, forcing me to watch the whole thing until 3 am in the morning, Clockwork-Orange style.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After an exhausted struggle, I managed to get up. I attempted to meditate, but my speaker system kept automatically turning on and playing very loud music, and I was forced to give up my efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I sat down to read my hardbound copy of Aristotle's &quot;Eudemian Ethics&quot; over breakfast, my iPad kept walking across the pages, leaving me with no choice but to check my email instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;mid-morning&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mid-Morning&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feeling the need for companionship, I began to text a friend on my phone, asking if they wanted to meet up later in the day. Unfortunately, the texting app kept closing and opening Facebook instead, where it proceeded to automatically scroll and force me to look at the updates in my &quot;news&quot; feed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time I attempted to re-open the text messaging app, I would instead be redirected to a photo album of a distant acquaintances' latest life adventures, making me feel inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's so painfully true that Facebook aggravates depression: how could it not when we're so powerless to avoid using it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;afternoon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Afternoon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do some writing, and also knew how impossible such a task would be in my circumstances. Not one to be defeated by some glowing LCD demon, I grabbed my pen and paper, abandoned my laptop AND cell phone, and opened the door to relocate to a quiet, wooded area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My gadgets knew what I was up to, and sent a series electromagnetic pulses into the electric wiring of my apartment; this created a force field that rendered me physically unable to leave. I had no choice but to stay inside and watch Netflix instead. How am I supposed to get any meaningful work done when I'm physically barred from doing so?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;evening&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Evening&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At last, it was time to prepare for my date later that night. I had met a woman previously that week, and we had instantly connected over our mutual senses of intellectual curiosity and personal responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Unfortunately, my laptop had other plans for the evening: its restraints fastened me to my chair, and its screen displayed a sequence of pornographic movies of increasingly explicit nature. Once again, my efforts at forming a deep, meaningful relationship with another were foiled by forces beyond my control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;an&amp;#95;appeal&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;humanity&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;An Appeal to Humanity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wasn't always this way: before computers and smart phones came along, I was surrounded by meaningful human relationships and refreshing intellectual stimulation. As human beings, we were free to go about our day as we saw fit, fully responsible for our actions and how we chose to spend our time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those greedy corporations forced us to buy their alienating products and made us use them in the ways we're so accustomed to today. Now, more than ever, we have to ask ourselves: Is all of this &quot;progress&quot; worth the price of our very souls, our humanity, and our free will?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400
</pubDate>
<author>
Michael Marsh
</author>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
